Guide to the Clippings File of the James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Clippings file of the James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection
1920-1985
JWJ MSS 89
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
117.42
(287 boxes)
The Clippings File of the James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection includes pamphlets and clippings documenting the African American experience in the twentieth century. The collection especially highlights the achievements of individual African Americans, the work of community and education organizations, and areas such as film, theater, music, sports, politics, and civil rights. The clippings were collected primarily by Langston Hughes, James Weldon and Grace Nail Johnson, Ollie Jewel Simms Okala (a friend and close associate of the Johnsons), and Carl Van Vechten, with some additional materials added by others. Clippings in the collection are drawn from general news sources as well as national and regional newspapers and magazines with an African American focus. The majority of clippings are from New York, Ohio, Arkansas, Illinois, and Pennsylvania newspapers. The collection also includes pamphlets and ephemera.
James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection of Negro Arts and Letters (Yale University)
Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967
Johnson, Grace Nail, 1885-1976
Okala, Ollie Jewell Sims, 1908-2001
Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection of documents acquired by gift and purchase from various sources. Source information is recorded on some items. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Clippings File of the James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection include pamphlets and clippings documenting various aspects of the African American experience in the twentieth century. The collection especially highlights the achievements of individual African Americans, the work of community and education organizations, and areas such as film, theater, music, sports, politics, and civil rights. The clippings were collected primarily by Langston Hughes, James Weldon and Grace Nail Johnson, Ollie Jewel Simms Okala (a friend and close associate of the Johnsons), and Carl Van Vechten, with some additional materials added by others. Clippings in the collection are drawn from national and regional news sources as well as newspapers and magazines with an African American focus. The majority of clippings are from New York, Ohio, Arkansas, Illinois, and Pennsylvania newspapers. The collection also includes pamphlets and ephemera.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: Series I. Pamphlets. Series II. Personal/Corporate Names. Series III. General Subjects.
African American athletes; African American politicians; African American entertainers; African Americans -- Societies, etc.; African Americans -- Education; African Americans -- Civil rights; United States -- Race relations; Clippings (information artifacts); Ephemera (general object genre); Pamphlets; James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection of Negro Arts and Letters (Yale University)
- Pamphlets, Series I
  - A - general, 4 (Box 1)
  - B - general, 4 (Box 2)
  - C - general (Box 3)
  - D - general, 3 (Box 3)
  - E - general, 2 (Box 4)
  - F - general, 2 (Box 4)
  - G - general, 2 (Box 5)
  - H - general, 2 (Box 5)
  - H - general (continued), 5 (Box 6)
  - I - general (Box 7)
  - J - general, 2 (Box 7)
  - K - general (Box 7)
  - L - general, 4 (Box 8)
  - M - general, 4 (Box 9)
  - N - general, 3 (Box 10)
  - O - general, 2 (Box 10)
  - P - general, 2 (Box 11)
  - Queen, Hallie E. (Box 11)
  - R - general, 2 (Box 11)
  - S - general, 5 (Box 12)
  - S - general (continued), 4 (Box 13)
  - T - general, 3 (Box 14)
  - U - general, 4 (Box 14)
  - V - general (Box 15)
  - W - general, 3 (Box 15)
  - W - general (continued), 2 (Box 16)
  - Y-Z - general (Box 16)
- Personal/Corporate Names, Series II
  - Aaron, Henry, 1957-1974; 3 (Box 17)
  - Abdul, Raoul (Box 17)
  - Abernathy, Ralph D. (Box 17)
  - Abrahams, Peter (Box 17)
  - Actors Equity Association (Box 17)
  - Adams, Leslie (Box 17)
  - Adderley, Julian (Cannonball) (Box 17)
  - Addison, Adele, 1955-1960; 2 (Box 17)
  - Aden, Alonzo (Box 17)
  - African Academy of Arts and Research (Box 18)
  - African Aid Committee (Box 18)
  - African Cultural Group of U.S.A. and Canada (Box 18)
  - African-American Heritage Association (Box 18)
  - African-American Institute (Box 18)
  - African-American Students Foundation (Box 18)
  - Afro-Arts Bazaar, Inc. (Box 18)
  - Afro Arts Theatre and Cultural Center (Box 18)
  - Agricultural, Mechanical, and Normal College, Pine Bluff, Arkansas (Box 18)
  - Ailey, Alvin, 1958-1965 (Box 18)
  - Ailey, Alvin (continued), 1966-1979, undated; 4 (Box 19)
  - Aldridge, Ira (Box 19)
  - Alexander, Clifford (Box 20)
  - Ali, Muhammad, 1961-1967; 4 (Box 20)
  - Ali, Muhammad (continued), 1967-1971; 5 (Box 21)
  - Ali, Muhammad (continued), 1972-1975; 2 (Box 22)
  - Allen, Betty, 1954-1966; 5 (Box 22)
  - Allen, Jonelle (Box 23)
  - Alliance For a Safer New York (Box 23)
  - Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority (Box 23)
  - Alston, Charles (Box 23)
  - Amenia Conference (Box 23)
  - American Committee on Africa (Box 23)
  - American Council on Race Relations, 1945-1949; 2 (Box 23)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1964-1975; 6 (Box 24)
  - American Jewish Committee (continued), 2 (Box 25)
  - American Missionary Association (Box 25)
  - American Negro Music Festival (Box 25)
  - American Negro Ballet (Box 25)
  - American Negro Opera Company (Box 25)
  - American Negro Theatre, 1943-1948; 2 (Box 25)
  - American Peace Crusade (Box 25)
  - American Society of African Culture, 1958-1965; 5 (Box 26)
  - American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers, 1943-1967; 3 (Box 26)
  - American Women's Voluntary Services, 2 (Box 27)
  - American Youth for Democracy (Box 27)
  - Americans for Democratic Action (Box 27)
  - Amos and Andy (Box 27)
  - Anderson, Eddie (Rochester) (Box 27)
  - Anderson, Garland (Box 27)
  - Anderson, Marian, 1925-1956; 4 (Box 27)
  - Anderson, Marian (continued), 1957-1964 (Box 28)
  - Andre, Jacqueline (Box 28)
  - Angelou, Maya (Box 28)
  - Apollo Theatre, undated (Box 28)
  - Archer, Osceola (Box 29)
  - Archibald, Julius (Box 29)
  - Armstead-Johnson, Helen (Box 29)
  - Armstrong, Henry (Box 29)
  - Armstrong, Louis, 1931-1969; 3 (Box 29)
  - Armstrong, Louis (continued), 1970-1971; 2 (Box 30)
  - Arroyo, Martina (Box 30)
  - Art for World Friendship (Box 30)
  - Ashe, Arthur, 1966-1970; 3 (Box 30)
  - Association for the Study of Afro-American Life and History (Box 31)
  - Association of Artists for Freedom (Box 31)
  - Atlanta University, 1926-1958; 6 (Box 31)
  - Attaway, Ruth (Box 31)
  - Bailey, Bill (Box 32)
  - Bailey, Pearl, 1943-1970; 5 (Box 32)
  - Baker, George, 1932-1939 (Box 33)
  - Baker, Josephine, 1925-1947 (Box 33)
  - Baker, Josephine (continued), 1948-1960; 5 (Box 34)
  - Baker, Josephine (continued), 1961-1966; 2 (Box 35)
  - Baldwin, James, 1942-1963; 3 (Box 35)
  - Baldwin, James (continued), 1963-1969; 4 (Box 36)
  - Ballet Americana (Box 36)
  - Les Ballets Africains (Box 36)
  - Balthrop, Carmen (Box 36)
  - Bambara, Toni Cade (Box 36)
  - Banneker. Benjamin (Box 36)
  - Baraka, Imanu Amiri, 1960-1970; 5 (Box 37)
  - Barnes, Mae (Box 37)
  - Barthe, Richmond, 1930-1943; 2 (Box 38)
  - Basie, William (Box 38)
  - Bass, George Houston (Box 38)
  - Bassey, Shirley (Box 38)
  - Battle, Samuel J. (Box 38)
  - Bearden, Romare, 1940-1968; 2 (Box 39)
  - Beatty, Talley (Box 39)
  - Béchet, Sidney (Box 39)
  - Belafonte, Harry, 1948-1960; 4 (Box 39)
  - Belafonte, Harry (continued), 1961, undated; 2 (Box 40)
  - Benedict College (Box 40)
  - Benga, Feral (Box 40)
  - Bennett, Hal (Box 40)
  - Bennett, Lerone (Box 40)
  - Bethune-Cookman College (Box 40)
  - Bethune, Mary McLeod (Box 40)
  - Bishop College (Box 40)
  - Black Academy of Arts and Letters (Box 40)
  - Black Muslims, 1959-1971; 6 (Box 41)
  - Black Panther Party, 1967-1971; 3 (Box 42)
  - Black Scholar (Box 42)
  - Black Theatre Alliance (Box 42)
  - Blake, Eubie (Box 42)
  - Blakey, Art (Box 42)
  - Bland, James A. (Box 42)
  - Blassingame, John W. (Box 42)
  - Bledsoe, Jules (Box 42)
  - Blue, Vida (Box 42)
  - Boatwright, McHenry (Box 43)
  - Boles, Robert (Box 43)
  - Bolin, Jane M. (Box 43)
  - Bolling, Leslie (Box 43)
  - Bond, Julian (Box 43)
  - Bonds, Margaret (Box 43)
  - Bontemps, Arna, 1936-1960 (Box 43)
  - Bontemps, Arna (continued), 1961 (Box 44)
  - Bontemps, Arna and Countee Cullen (Box 44)
  - Bosan, Alonzo (Box 44)
  - Bradley, Thomas (Box 44)
  - Braithwaite, Edward Ricardo (Box 44)
  - Braithwaite, William Stanley (Box 44)
  - Branch, William (Box 44)
  - Brawley, Benjamin (Box 44)
  - Brewer, John Mason (Box 44)
  - Brice, Carol (Box 44)
  - Brice, Eugene (Box 44)
  - Brice, Jonathan (Box 44)
  - Bricktop (Ada Smith du Conge) (Box 44)
  - Broadside Press (Box 45)
  - Brooke, Edward (Box 45)
  - Brooks, Gwendolyn (Box 45)
  - Brower, William, 1951-1972; 2 (Box 45)
  - Brown, Anne (Box 45)
  - Brown, Claude (Box 45)
  - Brown, Frank London (Box 45)
  - Brown, H. Rap (Box 45)
  - Brown, James (Box 45)
  - Brown, James Nathaniel (Box 45)
  - Brown, John (Box 46)
  - Brown, Marie Joe (Box 46)
  - Brown, Oscar Jr. (Box 46)
  - Brown, Sterling Allen (Box 46)
  - Browne, Roscoe Lee (Box 46)
  - Bruce, Mary (Box 46)
  - Buck, Pearl (Box 46)
  - Bullins, Ed (Box 46)
  - Bumbry, Grace, 1960-1964; 2 (Box 46)
  - Bunche, Ralph, 1948-1959; 3 (Box 47)
  - Burke, Georgia (Box 47)
  - Burke, Selma (Box 47)
  - Burleigh, Harry Thacker (Box 47)
  - Burrows, Vinie (Box 47)
  - Burton, Miriam (Box 47)
  - Butcher, Margaret Just (Box 47)
  - Caldwell, Erskine (Box 48)
  - Calloway, Cab (Box 48)
  - Calloway, Paul (Box 48)
  - Cambridge, Godfrey (Box 48)
  - Camp, Willowemoc (Box 48)
  - Campbell, E. Simms (Box 48)
  - Campanella, Roy (Box 48)
  - Capers, Virginia (Box 48)
  - Carmichael, Stokely (Box 49)
  - Carpenter, Thelma (Box 49)
  - Carroll, Diahann, 1954-1968; 4 (Box 49)
  - Carroll, Vinette (Box 50)
  - Carter, Elmer Anderson (Box 50)
  - Carter, Ralph (Box 50)
  - Carver, George Washington (Box 50)
  - George Washington Carver School (Box 50)
  - Cary, Mary Ann Shadd (Box 50)
  - Cayton, Horace R. (Box 50)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions (Box 50)
  - Chamberlain, Wilt (Box 50)
  - Charles, Ezzard (Box 50)
  - Charles, Ray (Box 51)
  - Charter Group for a Pledge of Conscience (Box 51)
  - Checker, Chubby (Box 51)
  - Chemchemi Cultural Center (Box 51)
  - Chesnutt, Charles W. (Box 51)
  - Chicago Negro Art Theatre (Box 51)
  - Chicago Negro Opera Guild (Box 51)
  - Childress, Alice (Box 51)
  - Chisholm, Shirley (Box 51)
  - Cinque (Box 51)
  - Citizens Emergency Defense Conference (Box 51)
  - Civil Rights Congress, 1946-1951; 4 (Box 52)
  - Clark College (Box 52)
  - Clark, Kenneth Bancroft (Box 52)
  - Clarke, John Henrik (Box 52)
  - Cleaver, Eldridge (Box 52)
  - Clement, Rufus Early (Box 52)
  - Clemente, Roberto (Box 52)
  - Coffee Concerts (Box 53)
  - Cohrs, Timothy (Box 53)
  - Cole, Nat King (Box 53)
  - Coleman, Leo (Box 53)
  - Coleman, Ornette (Box 53)
  - Coleman, William T. (Box 53)
  - Coleridge-Taylor, Samuel (Box 53)
  - Collins, Janet (Box 53)
  - Colored Orphan Asylum (Riverdale-on-Hudson, NY) (Box 53)
  - Coltrane, John (Box 53)
  - Commission on Human Relations (Box 54)
  - Commission on Interracial Cooperation (Box 54)
  - Committee for Equal Justice for Mrs. Recy Taylor (Box 54)
  - Committee for the Negro in the Arts (Box 54)
  - Committee for United Negro Relief (Box 54)
  - Committee of Conscience Against Apartheid (Box 54)
  - Committee of Friends (Box 54)
  - Committee on Civil Rights in Manhattan (Box 54)
  - Committee to Aid the Monroe Defendants (Box 54)
  - Committee to End Discrimination in Stuyvesant Town (Box 54)
  - Committee to Present the Truth about the Name "Negro" (Box 54)
  - Common Council for American Unity (Box 54)
  - Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), 1959-1964; 2 (Box 54)
  - Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) (continued), 1964, undated; 2 (Box 55)
  - Connelly, Mark, 1930-1931; 2 (Box 55)
    General note
    The Green Pastures
  - Cook, Gerald (Box 55)
  - Cook, Sam (Box 55)
  - Cook, Will Marion (Box 55)
  - Coordinating Council for Negro Performers (Box 55)
  - Cortor, Eldzier (Box 55)
  - Cosby, Bill (Box 56)
  - Cosme, Eusebia (Box 56)
  - Council Against Intolerance in America (Box 56)
  - Council for Democracy (Box 56)
  - Council on African Affairs, 1942-1946; 2 (Box 56)
  - Covarrubias, Miguel (Box 56)
  - Crichlow, Ernest (Box 56)
  - Crump, Paul (Box 56)
  - Cullen, Countee, 1925-1957; 2 (Box 56)
  - Cullen, F. A. (Black History Month) (Box 56)
  - Cunard, Nancy (Box 56)
  - D.C. Black Repertory Company (Box 57)
  - Dafora, Asadata (Box 57)
  - Dance Theatre of Harlem (Box 57)
  - Dandridge, Dorothy (Box 57)
  - Daniels, Jimmie (Box 57)
  - Dasein (Box 57)
  - Davis, Angela (Box 57)
  - Davis, Benjamin J, Jr. (Box 57)
  - Davis, Benjamin Oliver Sr. (Box 57)
  - Davis, Benjamin Oliver Jr. (Box 57)
  - Davis, Charles Till (Box 58)
  - Davis, Clifton (Box 58)
  - Davis, Ellabelle (Box 58)
  - Davis, Miles (Box 58)
  - Davis, Ossie, 1949-1969; 4 (Box 58)
  - Davis, Sammy Jr., 1955-1967; 5 (Box 59)
  - Davy, Gloria (Box 59)
  - Dawn, Marpessa (Box 60)
  - Dawson, William L., 2 (Box 60)
  - Day, Carita (Box 60)
  - De Carava, Roy (Box 60)
  - De Lavallade, Carmen (Box 60)
  - De Paur, Leonard (Box 60)
  - Dean, Phillip Hayes (Box 60)
  - Dee, Ruby (Box 60)
  - Dehn, Mura (Box 60)
  - Delta Sigma Theta (Box 60)
  - Demby, Edward Thomas (Box 60)
  - Demby, William (Box 60)
  - DePriest, James (Box 60)
  - Destine, Jean Leon (Box 61)
  - Dett, Robert Nathaniel (Box 61)
  - Dillard University (Box 61)
  - Dilworth, Hubert (Box 61)
  - Dixon, Dean, 1934-1946; 2 (Box 61)
  - Dixon, Ivan (Box 61)
  - Dobbs, Mattiwilda, 1951-1959; 4 (Box 62)
  - Dodson, Owen, 1939-1957; 2 (Box 62)
  - Douglas, Aaron (Box 63)
  - Douglass, Frederick, 1898-1938; 2 (Box 63)
  - Dra Mu Opera Company (Box 63)
  - Drew, Charles (Box 63)
  - Dubois, William Edward Burghardt, 1898-1964; 6 (Box 64)
  - Dumas, Alexandre (Box 65)
  - Dunbar, Paul Laurence (Box 65)
  - Dunbar, Rudolph, 1930-1945; 2 (Box 65)
  - Dunbar High School (Washington, D.C.) (Box 65)
  - Duncan, Todd, 1941-1948; 2 (Box 65)
  - Dunham, Katharine, 1940-1950; 3 (Box 66)
  - Du Sable Community Center (Chicago) (Box 66)
  - D'usseau, Arnaud and James Gow (Box 66)
    Deep Are the Roots
  - Ebony Magazine, 1950, undated; 2 (Box 66)
  - Eckstine, Billy (Box 67)
  - Edmonds, S. Randolph (Box 67)
  - Edmondson, William (Box 67)
  - Edwards, James (Box 67)
  - Elder, Lee (Box 67)
  - Elder, Lonne (Box 67)
  - Ellington, Duke, 1930-1959; 4 (Box 67)
  - Ellington, Duke (continued), 1960-1974; 5 (Box 68)
  - Duke Ellington Jazz Society (Box 69)
  - Ellison, Ralph, 1945-1964; 2 (Box 69)
  - Embree, Edwin R. (Box 69)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee (Box 69)
  - Encampment for Citizenship (Box 69)
  - Enwonwu, Ben (Box 69)
  - Ethiopian Art Theatre (Box 69)
  - Evanti, Lillian (Box 69)
  - Evers, Charles (Box 69)
  - Evers, Medgar (Box 69)
  - Fair Employment Practices Commission (Box 70)
  - Fair Play for Cuba Committee, 1960-1961; 2 (Box 70)
  - Falana, Lola (Box 70)
  - Fanon, Frantz (Box 70)
  - Fauset, Jessie (Box 70)
  - Federal Council of Churches, 1924-1947; 3 (Box 70)
  - Federal Theatre Project (Box 71)
  - Fetchit, Stepin (Box 71)
  - Fisher, Rudolph (Box 71)
  - Fisk University
    - General, 1925-1930, undated; 4 (Box 71)
    - General (continued), 1933-1964; 7 (Box 72)
    - General (continued), 1965 (Box 73)
    - Press Releases, 1946-1951; 6 (Box 73)
    - Institute of Race Relations (Box 74)
    - Festival of Music and Art, 1932-1958; 3 (Box 74)
    - Galleries and Collections, 1943-1950; 2 (Box 74)
    - Jubilee Singers and Choirs (Box 74)
    - Dramatic Productions (Box 74)
  - Fitzgerald, Ella, 1941-1960; 2 (Box 75)
  - Flack, Roberta (Box 75)
  - Flipper, Henry Ossian (Box 75)
  - Florida Agricultural and Mechanical University (Box 75)
  - Flowers, Tiger (Box 75)
  - Foreman, George (Box 75)
  - Foster, Gloria (Box 75)
  - Fowler, Manet Harrison (Box 75)
  - Foxx, Redd (Box 75)
  - Franklin, Aretha (Box 75)
  - Franklin, John Hope (Box 75)
  - Frazier, E. Franklin (Box 75)
  - Frazier, Joe (Box 75)
  - Free Southern Theater (Box 76)
  - Freedom House, 1949-1966; 2 (Box 76)
  - Freedomways Magazine (Box 76)
  - Freeman, Al Jr. (Box 76)
  - Freeman, H. Lawrence (Box 76)
  - Friendship House, 1942-1961; 2 (Box 76)
  - Fuller, Lorenzo (Box 76)
  - Gaines, Ernest J. (Box 77)
  - Galamison, Milton Arthur (Box 77)
  - Garner, Errol (Box 77)
  - Garvey, Marcus, 1925-1930; 2 (Box 77)
  - Gavilan, Kid (Box 77)
  - Gaye, Marvin (Box 77)
  - Gayle, Addison Jr. (Box 77)
  - Genet, Jean (Box 77)
    The Blacks
  - George, Zelma (Box 77)
  - Gershwin, George, 1928-1961; 7 (Box 78)
    Porgy and Bess
  - Gibson, Althea, 1950-1958; 3 (Box 79)
  - Gibson, Bob (Box 79)
  - Gibson, Kenneth (Box 79)
  - Gilbert, Mercedes (Box 79)
  - Gillespie, Dizzy (Box 80)
  - Gilliam, Sam (Box 80)
  - Gilpin, Charles S. (Box 80)
  - Giovanni, Nikki (Box 80)
  - Girvin, Virginia (Box 80)
  - Golden, Harry (Box 80)
  - Gordon, Robert H. (Box 80)
  - Gordon, Taylor (Box 80)
  - Gordone, Charles (Box 80)
  - Gossett, Louis (Box 80)
  - Grace, Charles Manuel (Daddy) (Box 81)
  - Graham, Shirley (Box 81)
  - Grant, Cy (Box 81)
  - Grant, Micki (Box 81)
  - Green, Paul (Box 81)
  - Gregory, Dick, 1961-1966; 2 (Box 81)
  - Grier, Roosevelt (Box 81)
  - Griffith, Emile (Box 81)
  - Grist, Reri, 1959-1963; 2 (Box 81)
  - Guillaume, Robert (Box 82)
  - Guillen, Nicolas (Box 82)
  - Gumby Collection (Columbia University) (Box 82)
  - Gunn, Moses (Box 82)
  - Gwaltney, John Langston (Box 82)
  - Hackley, E. Azalia (Box 82)
    The E. Azalia Hackley Memorial Collection, Detroit Public Library
  - Haley, Alex (Box 82)
  - Hall, Juanita, 1941-1962; 3 (Box 82)
  - Hamer, Fannie Lou (Box 82)
  - Hammerstein, Oscar, II (Box 83)
    Carmen Jones
  - Hampton, Lionel (Box 83)
  - Hampton, Fred (Box 83)
  - Hampton Institute, 1885-1970; 4 (Box 83)
  - Handy, William C., 1897-1955; 4 (Box 84)
  - Hansberry, Lorraine, 1959-1973; 5 (Box 85)
  - Hansberry, William Leo (Box 85)
  - Hardison, Inge (Box 86)
  - Harlem Cultural Council (Box 86)
  - Harlem Experimental Theatre (Box 86)
  - Harlem Opera Society (Box 86)
  - Harlem Suitcase Theatre (Box 86)
  - Harlem Workshop Studio (Box 86)
  - Harmon Foundation (Box 86)
  - Harper, Michael (Box 86)
  - Harrington, Oliver W. (Box 86)
  - Harris, Julius (Box 86)
  - Harris, Margaret (Box 86)
  - Harris, Patricia (Box 86)
  - Harrison, Richard B. (Box 86)
  - HARYOU-Act, Inc., 1963-1965; 3 (Box 86)
  - Hastie, William Henry (Box 87)
  - Hatch-Billops Collection (Box 87)
  - Hatcher, Richard G. (Box 87)
  - Hawkins, Coleman (Box 87)
  - Hayden, Robert (Box 87)
  - Hayes, Isaac (Box 87)
  - Hayes, Lola (Box 87)
  - Hayes, Roland, 1919-1950; 3 (Box 87)
  - Haynes, Daniel (Box 87)
  - Haynes, Eugene (Box 87)
  - Haynes, Hilda (Box 87)
  - Haynes, Lemuel (Box 87)
  - Heard, Nathan C. (Box 88)
  - Charles F. Heartman Collection (Box 88)
  - Heath, Gordon (Box 88)
  - Hedgeman, Anna (Box 88)
  - Hedgeman, Merritt, 2 (Box 88)
  - Hedgerow Theatre (Box 88)
  - Henderson, Fletcher (Box 88)
  - Hendrix, Jimi (Box 88)
  - Henson, Matthew (Box 88)
  - Hercules, Frank (Box 88)
  - Hernandez, Juano (Box 88)
  - Herndon, Angelo (Box 88)
  - Heyward, Dorothy and DuBose (Box 88)
  - Hill, Abram (Box 88)
  - Hill, Errol (Box 88)
  - Hill, Roy (Box 88)
  - Himes, Chester, 1945-1953; 2 (Box 89)
  - Hinderas, Natalie (Box 89)
  - Hines, Earl (Box 89)
  - Hinkson, Mary (Box 89)
  - Hogan, Ernest (Box 89)
  - Holder, Geoffrey, 1953-1960 (Box 89)
  - Holiday, Billie, 1941-1960; 3 (Box 90)
  - Holland, Charles (Box 90)
  - Holland, Jerome H. (Box 90)
  - Holloman, Charlotte (Box 90)
  - Holly, Ellen (Box 90)
  - Holt, Nora (Box 90)
  - Hooks, Robert (Box 91)
  - Hope, John (Box 91)
  - Hopkins, Linda (Box 91)
  - Horne, Lena, 1943-1969; 5 (Box 91)
  - Hoskins, Sheldon (Box 92)
  - Howard University
    - General, 1920-1960; 4 (Box 92)
    - Howard University Players, 1934-1949 (Box 92)
    - Howard University Players (continued), 1950-1960; 2 (Box 93)
    - Gallery of Art (Box 93)
  - Huey, Richard (Box 93)
  - Hunter, Charlayne (Box 93)
  - Hunton, Alphaeus (Box 93)
  - Hurston, Zora Neale, 1933-1950; 2 (Box 93)
  - Samuel Huston College (Box 94)
  - Hyman, Earle, 1946-1961; 3 (Box 94)
  - Improved Benevolent and Protective Order of Elks of the World, 1935-1972; 2 (Box 94)
  - Independent Citizens Committee of the Arts, Sciences, and Professions, Inc. (Box 94)
  - Indian Hill Summer Camp (Box 95)
  - Ingram, Rex (Box 95)
  - Institute of Race Relations (Society of Friends) (Box 95)
  - Institute on Human Relations (University of North Carolina) (Box 95)
  - International League for the Rights of Man (Box 95)
  - International Publishers (Box 95)
  - International School of Performing Arts (New York City) (Box 95)
  - International Workers Order (Box 95)
  - Jack, Hulan (Box 95)
  - Jackman, Harold (Box 95)
  - Jackson, George (Box 95)
  - Jackson, Levi (Box 95)
  - Jackson, Jesse (Box 95)
  - Jackson, Mahalia, 1954-1960; 2 (Box 96)
  - Jackson, Maynard (Box 96)
  - Jackson College (Box 96)
  - James, C.L.R. (Box 96)
  - James, Daniel, Jr. (Chappie) (Box 96)
  - James, Gee Gee (Box 96)
  - Jamison, Judith (Box 96)
  - Jarboro, Caterina (Box 96)
  - Jefferson School of Social Science (New York City) (Box 96)
  - Jessye, Eva (Box 96)
  - Joans, Ted (Box 96)
  - John, Errol (Box 97)
  - Johnson, Charles S., 2 (Box 97)
  - Johnson, Georgia Douglas (Box 97)
  - Johnson, Grace Nail (Box 97)
  - Johnson, Hall, 1926-1947; 3 (Box 97)
  - Johnson, Helen Louise (Dillette) (Box 97)
  - Johnson, Jack (Box 98)
  - Johnson, James Weldon
    - General, 1894-1937; 6 (Box 98)
    - General (continued), 1938-1973, undated; 6 (Box 99)
    - Works, general, 1913-1940; 4 (Box 100)
    - Works, individual
      - Along This Way (Box 100)
      - The Autobiography of an Ex-Colored Man (Box 100)
      - Black Manhattan (Box 100)
      - God's Trombones, 1920-1969; 4 (Box 101)
      - "Lift Every Voice and Sing" (Box 101)
      - Negro Americans, What Now? (Box 101)
      - Saint Peter Relates an Incident (Box 101)
    - James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection, Yale University, 1943-1950; 2 (Box 102)
    - The JWJ Literary Guild (Box 102)
    - JWJ Community Center (Box 102)
    - JWJ Homes, New York, 1940-1945; 2 (Box 102)
    - JWJ Homes, Philadelphia, 1939-1941; 2 (Box 103)
    - JWJ High School, Yorktown, Virginia (Box 103)
    - Institutions named for JWJ (Box 103)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 103)
  - Johnson, John H. (Box 103)
  - Johnson, James P. (Box 103)
  - Johnson, J. Rosamund (Box 103)
  - Johnson, Louis (Box 103)
  - Johnson, Mildred (Box 103)
  - Johnson, William H. (Box 103)
  - Jones, Elayne (Box 104)
  - Jones, James Earl, 1958-1970; 4 (Box 104)
  - Jones, Quincy (Box 104)
  - Jones, Prophet (Box 104)
  - Jones, Robert Earl (Box 104)
  - Joplin, Scott, 1971-1974; 2 (Box 105)
  - Jordan, Barbara (Box 105)
  - Jordan, June (Box 105)
  - Julian, Hubert (Box 105)
  - Julian, Percy (Box 105)
  - Karamu House, 1933-1948; 3 (Box 105)
  - Karamu House (continued), 1949-1956; 2 (Box 106)
  - Kay, Ulysses, 1944-1959; 2 (Box 106)
  - Kelley, William Melvin (Box 106)
  - Kennedy, Adrienne (Box 106)
  - Killens, John O. (Box 106)
  - Kilson, Martin (Box 106)
  - King, B.B. (Box 106)
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1956-1968; 5 (Box 107)
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr. (continued), 1968-1983; 5 (Box 108)
  - Kitt, Eartha, 1952-1960; 4 (Box 109)
  - Knight, Etheridge (Box 109)